A star’s trek for life, liberty, and love.
To Be Takei is a documentary film directed by Jennifer M. Kroot.
Over seven decades, actor and activist George Takei journeyed from a World War II internment camp to the helm
of the Starship Enterprise, and then to the daily news feeds of five million Facebook fans.
Join George and his husband, Brad, on a wacky and
profound trek for life, liberty, and love.
Self, played by George Takei.
Self, played by Brad Takei.
Self, played by Walter Koenig.
Self, played by William Shatner.
Self, played by Leonard Nimoy.
Self, played by Nichelle Nichols.
George Takei ( tə-KAY; born Hosato Takei, April 20, 1937)
is an American actor, author and activist.
He is known for his role as Hikaru Sulu, helmsman of the USS Enterprise in the
Star Trek franchise, and Galactus in The Super Hero Squad Show.
Takei was born to Japanese-American parents, with whom he lived in
Tule Lake Segregation Center during World War II.
He began pursuing acting in college, which led in 1965 to the role of
Sulu, to which he returned periodically into the 1990s.
Upon coming out as gay in 2005, he became a prominent proponent of
LGBT rights and active in state and local politics.
He has been a vocal advocate of the rights of immigrants, in part through his work on
the 2012 Broadway show Allegiance, about the internment experience.
Takei spoke both English and Japanese growing up and
remains fluent in both languages.
He has won several awards and accolades for his work on human rights and Japan–United States relations,
including his work with the Japanese American National Museum in Los Angeles, California.